<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Life | Adrian Artiles]]></title>
  <link href="http://AdrianArtiles.com/categories/life/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://AdrianArtiles.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-03-01T19:44:54-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://AdrianArtiles.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Adrian Artiles]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[adrian.r.artiles@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Write Like You Mean It]]></title>
    <link href="http://AdrianArtiles.com/write-like-you-mean-it"/>
    <updated>2013-12-22T23:43:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://AdrianArtiles.com/write-like-you-mean-it</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It has been one year and one day since my last post. That is a problem.</p>

<p>Earlier this week on a sidewalk I loudly proclaimed that I will write more often and regularly. This was never a real goal for me in the past, however I have decided that writing has become a priority for me, and chances are this is something you have considered too.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>There are plenty of good reasons to write regularly. A body of written work gives you a log, or at least a sample, of things that you have experienced. And this is a log that can be shared with the world. This makes it easier for people to get a sense of who you are before ever even meeting you, or possibly further information after having met you.</p>

<p>If you make a habit enough of writing, I feel it also helps enforce who you are. You begin to reflect more on what you are writing, what you are thinking, and what you are confident in communicating with everyone. It forces you to be congruent with yourself; no being one person to one group and another person to a different group. Old friends and future employers alike will read the same pieces. I think that is both powerful and awesome.</p>

<p>Writing also allows you to share what you have learned, and I promise you, you have something to teach. And as writing is a form of teaching, it will help solidify what you know. Win win.</p>

<p>However there have been reasons that have kept me from writing more regularly in the past; I find writing difficult, I spend way too much time finishing a piece, I wonder if there is a better use of my time (maybe I should refactor that app&hellip;), etc..</p>

<p>My answers to my old grievances;</p>

<p>Yes writing is difficult, at least it is for me. Can you guess how I can become better at writing? Practice, following through, and experience. As simple as that. Writing helps you become a better communicator, which I believe to be very important and worth the effort.</p>

<p>I do take a disproportionate amount of time to write an article. This is because I nitpick and stress about each word choice. I need to focus on not being such a perfectionist and instead focus on &ldquo;shipping&rdquo; (can easily draw plenty of analogies between shipping articles and shipping features; It&rsquo;s better to get something out the door that does the job, and get better at shipping increasingly quality work over time, rather then delivering nothing at all).</p>

<p>Is there a more efficient use of my time? Not if I focus on being more concise and focused with my writing efforts. Now with the &ldquo;lowered cost&rdquo; of writing more, the benefits definitely out-weigh the costs.</p>

<p>You should write too. This may help lower the barrier for you (it helped me); start writing down a list of different things you want to write about. I keep this list in Evernote. After you have a few ideas, pick one, and just start writing down some sentences in a text editor, just for yourself. If you are anything like me, you&rsquo;ve probably already written most of it in an internal monologue to yourself, now you just need to write it down. Once you have a draft down, read it, rewrite it from scratch quickly, and just throw it online somewhere. Don&rsquo;t over think it, you just need to start somewhere. At least that&rsquo;s what I&rsquo;ve started to do.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m excited to get more of myself on here.</p>

<p>Talk to you soon,</p>

<p>Adrian</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
